Software Consultant

SEAN FARIA

Phone: (305) 301-7140 | Email: sfari004@gmail.com

Website: http://seanfaria.com

Address: 22429 SW 88th path, Cutler Bay, Florida 33190

Objective

I am currently working as a Software Consultant with over 3 years of hands-on experience in Development, Architecture, and Production Environments. Seeking a position where my technical background and continued growth and interests are supported for our bilateral success. I am looking forward to new challenges.

Skills and Certifications

Technology

AWS, Azure, SQL Server 2008/2012/2016, PowerShell, JavaScript, SQL/T-SQL, XML/HTML, CSS, Linux, Apache Tomcat, Windows Server 2008/2012/2016, Serverless, GIT

Certification

AWS Cloud Practitioner – March 2018 AWS Solutions Architect – August 2018

Work Experience

SOFTWARE CONSULTANT - IB USA INC. - Sunrise, Florida - July 2016 - Present

- Automate patches, software upgrades, and backups using PowerShell and group policy.
- Provide level I/II and III support for ship to shore communication servers and software.
- Build, administer and maintain environments in AWS (Amazon Web Services) and Microsoft Azure.
- Perform QA testing on application to ensure that key features function in web environment.
- Develop and integrate solutions in PowerShell Scripting to maximize efficiency in transport using FTP/SFTP.
- Integrate highly available/fault tolerant cloud environments for customers using AWS/Azure best practices.
- SQL Server and Windows Server 2008/2012/2016 administrator
- Infrastructure analysis to diagnose connection issues between database servers and application servers using various security tools and networking techniques.

INTERN - BARRY UNIVERSITY - Miami Shores, Florida - Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

- Installed and configured computer hardware operating systems and applications.
- Assisted faculty in setting up two-factor authentication to login to workday.
- Troubleshooted issues on iPad, iPhone and Android devices.
- Identified, diagnosed and solved system hardware or software faults.
- Responsible for ensuring data sanitization on computer before repurposing, using dban.
- Prioritized and managed open tickets.
- Administered user account changes within active directory focusing on access controls.

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE-INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - Barry University - Miami Shores -2014-2016